Daniel Midwood

I am a functional programmer, focused on Clojure development, designing and implementing APIs, and scaling systems. I have further experience in Scala and JavaScript among other language and my background is in Java / JVM programming.

For the last year I have been traveling and working from various locations around the world.

Email: dan@danmidwood.com

Twitter: @djmidwood Skype: danmidwood

Phone: (+44) 020 8123 8132 Www: http://danmidwood.com

Github: https://github.com/danmidwood

Professional Experience

December 2013 ongoing: Nomadic Software Developer

I left the UK in November 2013 and have since been traveling through South America and Europe, working remotely from cities such as Krakow, Santiago and Buenos Aires. I've specialized in consulting, advising, and prototyping, particularly with functional languages on the JVM, and have also been involved in some more standard development work using Clojure, Scala, JavaScript, Java and Go. A few highlights:

- Guiding a migration of an application to the JVM, advising on modern Java programming, building, testing, and continuous integration and deployment
- Building an open source binary communication library in JavaScript (https://github.com/argotsdk/argot.js)
- Working with a games company to prototype scalable alternatives to their existing systems that were suffering under the strain of their success
- Using Golang and data inference techniques to fabricate missing values from data streams

During this time I have also been collaborating on a SaaS web application built in Clojure that is due to be released in Spring 2015, and an iOS mobile game that is slated for a late 2015 release.

May 2012 to October 2013: Mind Candy, London

I joined Mind Candy shortly after they began a transition from Java to Scala. As a member of the Moshi Monsters back end team I worked on the server side of the game as well as on the payments and the promotional offers services.

Later I moved to lead the back end development of the Moshling Rescue title, release on mobile platforms and Facebook.

Alongside my development work I was also involved in hiring new team members, and mentoring, particularly with regard to functional programming and good FP practices, and giving technical talks and demos to other developers.

- Moshi Monsters: http://mindcandy.com/products/moshi-monsters
- Moshling Rescue: http://mindcandy.com/products/moshling-rescue

June 2010 to May 2012: CPP, York

At CPP I worked with Groovy and JavaScript to create client labeled financial systems.

After some time with the company I moved into secondment with the architectural team where we worked to determine better ways to develop software, evaluate new software, libraries and techniques and give talks and present what we found to the company.

At CPP I acted as an advocate for improving relations between development and other departments, trying to more the organisation towards a more agile / devops mindset and culture.

January 2010 to June 2010: Liquid Logic, Leeds

Liquid Logic are a Leeds based startup building software for health and social care providers, I joined as an integration specialist when they were seeking to have their software share data with other systems.

This involved frequent and close collaboration with our clients and other software vendors, visiting client site and working with remote collaborators to best achieve our goals.

September 2007 to January 2010: Result Group, Elland

Result Group was the first software company that I worked for and one that gave me a great introduction to software development. At Result I learned about TDD, pair programming and other agile techniques. I worked to implement a continuous integration server to perform selenium-style tests on our Java client. Shortly into my time at Result I moved into the Innovations Team where we experimented and prototyped new technologies to meet client needs.

Education

2005 Computer Science BSc: Huddersfield University

A Computer Science degree with a particular emphasis on data, algorithms and artificial intelligence. For my dissertation I melded techniques of genetic algorithms and game theory to create a simulated solution to the Iterated Prisoner's Dilemma problem